Wyck Association Collection 1663-1972 Mss.Ms.Coll.52
American Philosophical Society
- Series V. Estate material, 1683-1967; 11.0 Linear feet 22 boxes
  - Caspar Wistar Haines I
    - Accounts, 1801-1807 (Box 205, Folder 40a)
    - Accounts, 1802-1809 (Box 205, Folder 41)
    - Accounts, n.d. (Box 205, Folder 42)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1795-1797 (Box 205, Folder 43)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1798-1799 (Box 205, Folder 44)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1800 (Box 205, Folder 45)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1801 (Box 205, Folder 46)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1802-1804 (Box 205, Folder 47)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1806-1836 (Box 205, Folder 48)
    - Bills and Receipts (Box 205, Folder 49)
    - Legal, 1801 (Box 205, Folder 50)
    - Receipts book, 1802-1803 (Box 205, Folder 51)
    - Receipts, 1801-1820 (Box 205, Folder 52)
  - Hannah Marshall Haines
    - Legal, 1833 (Box 205, Folder 53)
  - Reuben Haines III
    - Account book, 1843-1853 (Box 205, Folder 54)
    - Account book, 1847-1853 (Box 205, Folder 55)
    - Account book, 1860-1878 (Box 206, Folder 56)
    - Accounts: including 1831 account with Rembrandt Peale, 1831-1849 (Box 206, Folder 57)
    - Accounts, 1832 (Box 206, Folder 58)
    - Accounts, 1843-1866 (Box 206, Folder 59)
    - Accounts, 1849-1864 (Box 206, Folder 60)
    - Accounts, 1854-1860 (Box 206, Folder 61)
    - Accounts, 1860-1870 (Box 206, Folder 62)
    - Accounts, 1871-1878 (Box 206, Folder 63)
    - Accounts, 1877-1881 (Box 206, Folder 64)
    - Accounts, 1879-1885 (Box 206, Folder 65)
    - Accounts, n.d. (Box 206, Folder 66)
    - Banking: bank book, 1847-1853 (Box 206, Folder 67)
    - Banking: check stub books, 1841-1862 (Box 206, Folder 68)
    - Banking: Mechanics Bank, cancelled checks, 1857-1858 (Box 206, Folder 69)
    - Banking: Mechanics Bank, cancelled checks, 1858 (Box 206, Folder 70)
    - Banking: Mechanics Bank, cancelled checks, 1859 (Box 206, Folder 71)
    - Banking: Mechanics Bank, cancelled checks, 1860 (Box 207, Folder 72)
    - Banking: Mechanics Bank, cancelled checks, 1861 (Box 207, Folder 73)
    - Banking: Mechanics Bank, cancelled checks, 1861 (Box 207, Folder 74)
    - Banking: Mechanics Bank, cancelled checks, 1861 (Box 207, Folder 75)
    - Banking: Mechanics Bank, cancelled checks, 1862 (Box 207, Folder 76)
    - Banking: Mechanics Bank, cancelled checks, 1863 (Box 207, Folder 77)
    - Banking: Mechanics Bank, cancelled checks, 1863 (Box 207, Folder 78)
    - Banking: Mechanics Bank, cancelled checks, 1864 (Box 207, Folder 79)
    - Banking: Mechanics Bank, cancelled checks (Box 207, Folder 80)
    - Banking: Pennsylvania Co., cancelled checks, 1863-1864 (Box 207, Folder 81)
    - Banking: Provident Life and Trust Co., 1882 (Box 207, Folder 82)
    - Banking: Reliance Bank, bank book, 1859-1864 (Box 208, Folder 83)
    - Banking: miscellany, n.d. (Box 208, Folder 84)
    - Bills and receipts, 1832-1842 (Box 208, Folder 85)
    - Bills and receipts, 1843 (Box 208, Folder 86)
    - Bills and receipts, 1844-1848 (Box 208, Folder 87)
    - Bills and receipts, 1849-1850 (Box 208, Folder 88)
    - Bills and receipts, 1851 (Box 208, Folder 89)
    - Bills and receipts, 1852 (Box 208, Folder 90)
    - Bills and receipts, 1853 (Box 208, Folder 91)
    - Bills and receipts, 1853 (Box 208, Folder 92)
    - Bills and receipts, 1853 (Box 208, Folder 93)
    - Bills and receipts, 1853 (Box 208, Folder 94)
    - Bills and receipts, 1853 (Box 208, Folder 95)
    - Bills and receipts, 1854 (Box 208, Folder 96)
    - Bills and receipts, 1855 (Box 208, Folder 97)
    - Bills and receipts, 1856 (Box 208, Folder 98)
    - Bills and receipts, 1857 (Box 209, Folder 99)
    - Bills and receipts, 1858 (Box 209, Folder 100)
    - Bills and receipts, 1859 (Box 209, Folder 101)
    - Bills and receipts, 1860 (Box 209, Folder 102)
    - Bills and receipts, 1861 (Box 209, Folder 103)
    - Bills and receipts, 1862 (Box 209, Folder 104)
    - Bills and receipts, 1863 (Box 209, Folder 105)
    - Bills and receipts, 1864 (Box 209, Folder 106)
    - Bills and receipts, 1865 (Box 209, Folder 107)
    - Bills and receipts, 1866 (Box 209, Folder 108)
    - Bills and receipts, 1867 (Box 210, Folder 109)
    - Bills and receipts, 1868 (Box 210, Folder 110)
    - Bills and receipts, 1869 (Box 210, Folder 111)
    - Bills and receipts, 1870 (Box 210, Folder 112)
    - Bills and receipts, 1871 (Box 210, Folder 113)
    - Bills and receipts, 1872 (Box 210, Folder 114)
    - Bills and receipts, 1873 (Box 210, Folder 115)
    - Bills and receipts, 1874 (Box 210, Folder 116)
    - Bills and receipts, 1875 (Box 210, Folder 117)
    - Bills and receipts, 1876 (Box 210, Folder 118)
    - Bills and receipts, 1877 (Box 210, Folder 119)
    - Bills and receipts, 1878 (Box 211, Folder 120)
    - Bills and receipts, 1879 (Box 211, Folder 121)
    - Bills and receipts, 1880 (Box 211, Folder 122)
    - Bills and receipts, 1881 (Box 211, Folder 123)
    - Bills and receipts, 1882 (Box 211, Folder 124)
    - Bills and receipts (Box 211, Folder 125)
    - Legal materials, 1831-1889 (Box 211, Folder 126)
    - Legal materials, 1835-1880 (Box 211, Folder 127)
    - Legal materials, 1836-1858 (Box 211, Folder 128)
    - Legal materials, 1832-1877 (Box 211, Folder 129)
    - Legal materials, 1855 (Box 211, Folder 130)
    - Legal materials, 1889 (Box 211, Folder 131)
    - Legal materials, n.d. (Box 211, Folder 132)
    - Legal materials, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 133)
    - Legal materials, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 134)
    - Legal materials, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 135)
    - Memoranda book, 1831 (Box 212, Folder 136)
    - Miscellaneous business, 1864 (Box 212, Folder 137)
    - Miscellany, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 138)
    - Receipt book, 1841-1851 (Box 212, Folder 139)
    - Receipts book, 1849-1882 (Box 212, Folder 140)
    - Receipt book, 1858-1877 (Box 212, Folder 141)
  - Jane Bowne Haines I
    - Accounts, 1844 (Box 212, Folder 142)
    - Bills and receipts, 1841-1847 (Box 212, Folder 143)
    - Bills and receipts (Box 212, Folder 144)
    - Legal materials incl. inventory and division of household furniture, 1840-1843 (Box 212, Folder 145)
  - John Smith Haines II
    - Legal Material, 1819 (Box 213, Folder 146)
    - Legal material, 1855 (Box 213, Folder 147)
  - Ann Haines
    - Accounts, 1855-1870 (Box 213, Folder 148)
    - Accounts, 1869-1876 (Box 213, Folder 149)
    - Bills and receipts, 1830-1851 (Box 213, Folder 150)
    - Bills and receipts, 1857-1872 (Box 213, Folder 151)
    - Bills and receipts (Box 213, Folder 152)
    - Legal material, 1829-1847 (Box 213, Folder 153)
    - Legal material, 1850-1883 (Box 213, Folder 154)
    - Legal material, 1860 (Box 213, Folder 155)
    - Taxes, 1860-1869 (Box 213, Folder 156)
  - John Aston Warder
    - Legal materials, 1883 (Box 213, Folder 157)
  - Elizabeth Haines Warder
    - Legal materials, 1891 (Box 213, Folder 158)
  - Robert Bowne Haines I
    - Accounts, 1889-1898 (Box 213, Folder 159)
    - Accounts, 1900-1913 (Box 213, Folder 160)
    - Accounts, 1914-1931 (Box 213, Folder 161)
    - Bills and receipts, 1895-1896 (Box 213, Folder 162)
    - Bills and receipts, 1897-1928 (Box 213, Folder 163)
    - check book and account book, 1895-1899 (Box 213, Folder 164)
    - Journal, 1895-1896 (Box 214, Folder 165)
    - Journal, 1895-1896 (Box 214, Folder 166)
    - Journal, 1895-1896 (Box 214, Folder 167)
    - Legal material, 1890-1939 (Box 214, Folder 168)
    - Miscellaneous business incl. taxes, 1895-1926 (Box 214, Folder 169)
  - Margaret Vaux Wistar Haines
    - Accounts, 1917-1928 (Box 214, Folder 170)
    - Accounts, 1919-1920 (Box 214, Folder 171)
    - Accounts, 1921-1922 (Box 214, Folder 172)
    - Accounts, 1923-1924 (Box 214, Folder 173)
    - Accounts, 1925-1926 (Box 214, Folder 174)
    - Accounts, 1927-1939 (Box 214, Folder 175)
    - Banking, 1917-1918 (Box 214, Folder 176)
    - Banking, 1919-1920 (Box 214, Folder 177)
    - Banking, 1921-1922 (Box 215, Folder 178)
    - Banking, 1923-1924 (Box 215, Folder 179)
    - Banking, 1925-1926 (Box 215, Folder 180)
    - Banking, 1927-1929 (Box 215, Folder 181)
    - Banking, 1930-1931 (Box 215, Folder 182)
    - Banking, 1932-1933 (Box 215, Folder 183)
    - Banking, 1934-1935 (Box 215, Folder 184)
    - Banking, 1936-1937 (Box 215, Folder 185)
    - Banking, 1938-1940 (Box 215, Folder 186)
    - Bills and receipts, 1918-1926 (Box 215, Folder 187)
    - Inventories, 1917 (Box 215, Folder 188)
    - Legal materials, 1903 (Box 215, Folder 189)
    - Legal materials, 1917 (Box 215, Folder 190)
    - Legal materials, 1917 (Box 215, Folder 191)
    - Legal materials, 1918 (Box 215, Folder 192)
    - Legal materials, 1919 (Box 215, Folder 193)
    - Legal materials, 1920 (Box 215, Folder 194)
    - Legal materials, 1922 (Box 215, Folder 195)
    - Legal materials, 1924 (Box 215, Folder 196)
    - Legal materials, 1932 (Box 215, Folder 197)
    - Legal materials, 1937 (Box 215, Folder 198)
    - Letal materials, 1939 (Box 215, Folder 199)
    - Legal materials, 1940 (Box 215, Folder 200)
    - Miscellaneous business, 1924 (Box 215, Folder 201)
  - Jane Reuben Haines
    - Division of furniture at Wyck, 1862-1869 (Box 215, Folder 202)
    - Inventory and appraisal, incl. inventory re Ann Haines, 1912 (Box 215, Folder 203)
    - Legal material, 1910 (Box 215, Folder 204)
      Wills
    - Taxes, 1913-1926 (Box 215, Folder 205)
    - Taxes, 1917-1920 (Box 216, Folder 206)
    - Taxes, 1921-1925 (Box 216, Folder 207)
    - Taxes, 1926-1930 (Box 216, Folder 208)
    - Taxes, 1931-1935 (Box 216, Folder 209)
    - Taxes, 1936-1940 (Box 216, Folder 210)
    - Taxes, 1941-1947 (Box 216, Folder 211)
  - Caspar Wistar Haines II
    - Accounts, 1935-1940 (Box 216, Folder 212)
    - Banking, 1931-1942 (Box 216, Folder 213)
    - Banking, 1935-1937 (Box 216, Folder 214)
    - Banking, 1938-1939 (Box 216, Folder 215)
    - Banking, 1940-1942 (Box 216, Folder 216)
    - Banking, 1957-1959 (Box 216, Folder 217)
    - Banking, 1960-1962 (Box 216, Folder 218)
    - Banking, 1963-1964 (Box 216, Folder 219)
    - Banking, 1965-1967 (Box 216, Folder 220)
    - Bills and receipts, 1937-1939 (Box 216, Folder 221)
    - Legal material, 1933-1937 (Box 216, Folder 222)
    - Legal material, 1934 (Box 216, Folder 223)
    - Legal material, 1934 (Box 216, Folder 224)
    - Legal material, 1939 (Box 216, Folder 225)
    - Legal material, 1941 (Box 216, Folder 226)
    - Miscellaneous business, 1925-1932 (Box 216, Folder 227)
    - Miscellaneous business, 1933-1944 (Box 216, Folder 228)
    - Taxes, 1936-1940 (Box 216, Folder 229)
  - Robert Bowne Haines II
    - Accounts, 1918-1924 (Box 217, Folder 230)
    - Accounts, 1925-1929 (Box 217, Folder 231)
    - Accounts, 1930-1932 (Box 217, Folder 232)
    - Accounts, 1933-1934 (Box 217, Folder 233)
    - Accounts, 1934-1940 (Box 217, Folder 234)
    - Accounts, 1935-1936 (Box 217, Folder 235)
    - Accounts, 1937-1945 (Box 217, Folder 236)
    - Accounts, 1940-1941 (Box 217, Folder 237)
    - Accounts, 1941-1943 (Box 217, Folder 238)
    - Accounts, 1944-1945 (Box 218, Folder 239)
    - Accounts, 1946-1947 (Box 218, Folder 240)
    - Accounts, 1948-1954 (Box 218, Folder 241)
    - Banking, 1929-1939 (Box 218, Folder 242)
    - Banking, 1957-1967 (Box 218, Folder 243)
    - Legal material, 1917-1929 (Box 218, Folder 244)
    - Legal material, 1931-1933 (Box 218, Folder 245)
    - Legal material 1934-1940 (Box 218, Folder 246)
    - Miscellaneous 1938-1947 (Box 218, Folder 247)
  - Mary Morton Haines
    - Accounts, 1928-1929 (Box 218, Folder 248)
    - Accounts, 1930-1931 (Box 218, Folder 249)
    - Accounts, 1932-1933 (Box 218, Folder 250)
    - Accounts, 1934-1937 (Box 218, Folder 251)
    - Banking, 1928-1929 (Box 218, Folder 252)
    - Banking, 1930-1931 (Box 219, Folder 253)
    - Banking, 1932-1933 (Box 219, Folder 254)
    - Banking, 1934-1935 (Box 219, Folder 255)
    - Banking, 1936-1937 (Box 219, Folder 256)
    - Banking, 1938-1940 (Box 219, Folder 257)
    - Bills and receipts, 1928-1930 (Box 219, Folder 258)
    - Bills and receipts, 1931-1934 (Box 219, Folder 259)
    - Bills and receipts, 1933-1936 (Box 219, Folder 260)
    - Correspondence, 1932-1941 (Box 219, Folder 261)
    - Legal, 1892-1928 (Box 219, Folder 262)
    - Legal, 1927 (Box 219, Folder 263)
    - Legal, 1928 (Box 219, Folder 264)
    - Legal, 1929 (Box 219, Folder 265)
    - Legal, 1930 (Box 219, Folder 266)
    - Legal, 1939 (Box 219, Folder 267)
    - Taxes, 1928-1931 (Box 219, Folder 268)
    - Taxes, 1936-1937 (Box 219, Folder 269)
  - Jane Bowne Haines II
    - Accounts, 1933-1938 (Box 219, Folder 270)
    - Accounts, 1939-1944 (Box 219, Folder 271)
    - Bills and receipts, 1931-1946 (Box 219, Folder 272)
    - Bills and receipts (Box 219, Folder 273)
    - Inventory, n.d. (Box 219, Folder 274)
    - Legal material, 1937 (Box 219, Folder 275)
    - Miscellaneous, 1937-1945 (Box 219, Folder 276)
  - ALPHABETICAL LIST
    - Bowne Family
      - Legal, 1909-1910 (Box 219, Folder 277)
    - Margaret Brown
      - 1835-1836 (Box 219, Folder 278)
    - Bartholomew Coppock
      - Legal, 1683-1718 (Box 219, Folder 279)
    - Celia Creath
      - Accounts, 1895, 1919 (Box 220, Folder 280)
      - Legal, 1917 (Box 220, Folder 281)
      - Will. Sarah Lindley Fisher (Box 220, Folder 281a)
      - Will. J. M. Fox, 1918 (Box 220, Folder 281b)
    - Catharine Greenleafe
      - Legal, 1794 (Box 220, Folder 282)
    - John Haddock
      - Legal, 1788 (Box 220, Folder 283)
    - Walter Haddock
      - Legal, 1788 (Box 220, Folder 284)
    - William Haddock
      - Legal, 1790 (Box 220, Folder 285)
    - Josiah Haines I
      - Legal, 1728 (Box 220, Folder 286)
    - Josiah Haines II
      - Legal, 1795, 1799 (Box 220, Folder 287)
    - Mary Huston Haines
      - Banking, 1928 (Box 220, Folder 288)
      - Banking, 1929 (Box 220, Folder 289)
      - Banking, 1930 (Box 220, Folder 290)
      - Banking, 1931 (Box 220, Folder 291)
      - Banking, 1932-33 (Box 220, Folder 292)
      - Banking, 1933 (Box 220, Folder 293)
      - Banking, 1934 (Box 220, Folder 294)
      - Banking, 1935 (Box 220, Folder 295)
      - Banking, 1936 (Box 220, Folder 296)
      - Banking, 1937 (Box 220, Folder 297)
      - Banking, 1938 (Box 220, Folder 298)
      - Banking, 1939 (Box 220, Folder 299)
      - Banking, 1940 (Box 220, Folder 300)
      - Banking, 1941 (Box 220, Folder 301)
      - Banking, 1942 (Box 220, Folder 302)
      - Banking, 1943 (Box 220, Folder 303)
      - Banking, 1944 (Box 220, Folder 304)
      - Banking, 1945 (Box 220, Folder 305)
      - Banking, 1946 (Box 220, Folder 306)
      - Banking, 1947 (Box 220, Folder 307)
      - Banking, 1948 (Box 220, Folder 308)
      - Banking, 1949 (Box 220, Folder 309)
      - Banking, 1950 (Box 220, Folder 310)
      - Banking, 1951 (Box 220, Folder 311)
      - Banking, 1952 (Box 220, Folder 312)
      - Banking, 1953 (Box 221, Folder 313)
      - Banking, 1954 (Box 221, Folder 314)
      - Banking, 1955 (Box 221, Folder 315)
      - Banking, 1956 (Box 221, Folder 316)
      - Banking, 1957 (Box 221, Folder 317)
      - Banking, 1958 (Box 221, Folder 318)
      - Banking, 1959 (Box 221, Folder 319)
      - Banking, 1960 (Box 221, Folder 320)
      - Banking, 1961 (Box 221, Folder 321)
      - Banking, 1962 (Box 221, Folder 322)
      - Banking, 1963 (Box 221, Folder 323)
      - Banking, 1964 (Box 221, Folder 324)
      - Banking, 1965 (Box 221, Folder 325)
      - Banking, 1966 (Box 221, Folder 326)
      - Banking, 1967 (Box 221, Folder 327)
      - Banking (Miller Family), 1937-1960 (Box 221, Folder 328)
      - Legal, 1940 (Box 221, Folder 329)
      - Legal, 1944 (Box 221, Folder 330)
      - Legal, 1945 (Box 221, Folder 331)
      - Legal, 1946 (Box 221, Folder 332)
      - Legal, 1947 (Box 222, Folder 333)
      - Legal, 1948 (Box 222, Folder 334)
      - Legal, 1949 (Box 222, Folder 335)
      - Legal, 1957 (Box 222, Folder 336)
      - Tax Return, 1947 (Box 222, Folder 337)
      - Miscellany, 1944-47 (Box 222, Folder 338)
    - Richard Haines
      - Legal, 1744 (Box 222, Folder 339)
    - Theodora Harrison
      - Legal, 1942 (Box 222, Folder 340)
      - Miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 222, Folder 341)
    - Charlesanna L. Huston
      - Banking, 1925-1933 (Box 222, Folder 342)
      - Banking, 1934-1936 (Box 222, Folder 343)
      - Banking, 1937-1938 (Box 222, Folder 344)
      - Banking, 1939-1940 (Box 222, Folder 345)
      - Banking, 1941-1943 (Box 222, Folder 346)
      - Banking, 1944-1946 (Box 222, Folder 347)
      - Banking, 1947-1948 (Box 222, Folder 348)
      - Banking, 1949-1950 (Box 222, Folder 349)
      - Banking, 1951-1952 (Box 223, Folder 350)
      - Banking, 1953-1954 (Box 223, Folder 351)
      - Banking, 1955-1958 (Box 223, Folder 352)
      - Banking, 1959-1967 (Box 223, Folder 353)
      - Legal, 1924 (Box 223, Folder 354)
    - Franklin C. Jones
      - Accounts, 1897 (Box 223, Folder 355)
    - John Jones
      - Legal, 1785-1791 (Box 223, Folder 356)
    - Sarah F. Jones
      - Accounts, 1937-1939 (Box 223, Folder 357)
      - Banking, 1938-1941 (Box 223, Folder 358)
      - Banking, 1942-1947 (Box 223, Folder 359)
      - Bills and Receipts, 1933-1937 (Box 223, Folder 360)
      - Inventories, 1938 (Box 223, Folder 361)
      - Legal, 1937-1948 (Box 223, Folder 362)
      - Taxes, 1937-1938 (Box 223, Folder 363)
    - John Lukens
      - Accounts, 1764-1799 (Box 223, Folder 364)
    - Benjamin Marshall
      - Account book, 1778-1796 (Box 223, Folder 365)
    - Christopher Marshall
      - Legal, 1810-1813 (Box 223, Folder 366)
    - Sarah Marshall
      - Legal, 1797-1802 (Box 224, Folder 367)
    - Rebecca Martin
      - Bills and Receipts, 1797 (Box 224, Folder 368)
    - Timothy Matlack
      - Legal, 1750-1752 (Box 224, Folder 369)
    - Susan Scull
      - Taxes, 1934-1937 (Box 224, Folder 370)
    - John Tarte
      - Legal, 1789 (Box 224, Folder 371)
    - Elizabeth Voorhees
      - Accounts, 1912 (Box 224, Folder 372)
    - Rebecca Vanaken
      - Accounts, 1797 (Box 224, Folder 373)
    - Cynthia Wardell
      - Legal, 1878 (Box 224, Folder 374)
    - Lewis Warner
      - Bills and Receipts, 1872 (Box 224, Folder 375)
    - Elizabeth Bowne Warder
      - Account Book, 1882-1885 (Box 224, Folder 376)
    - J. Warder
      - Account, 1783 (Box 224, Folder 377)
    - Samuel Wallis
      - Accounts, 1776-1793 (Box 224, Folder 378)
    - C. Wharton
      - Memorandum, 1801 (Box 224, Folder 379)
    - Peter White
      - Legal, 1753-1762 (Box 224, Folder 380)
    - Caspar Wistar, M.D., Isaac J. Wistar
      - Legal, 1903, 1933 (Box 224, Folder 381)
    - Katherine J. Wistar, Lydia J. Wistar
      - Accounts, 1903 (Box 224, Folder 382)
      - Legal, 1902 (Box 224, Folder 383)
    - Richard Wistar
      - Legal, 1789 (Box 224, Folder 384)
    - Thomas Wistar, M.D.
      - Legal, 1913 (Box 224, Folder 385)
      - Miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 224, Folder 386)
      - Miscellaneous Estate Papers, 1816-1944 (Box 224, Folder 387)
  - OVERSIZED estate material
    - Books
      - Account Book - Reuben Haines III, 1849-1882 (Box PB1, Folder 152)
      - Check Stub Book - Estate of Reuben Haines III, 1858-1863 (Box OS4, Folder 18)
- Series VI. Legal material, 1684-1944; 3.25 Linear feet 8 boxes
  Included in Legal Materials are bonds, contracts, deeds, leases, mortgages, and promissory notes. The significance of these papers lies chiefly in their information about land ownership within the family.
  The legal documents regarding real estate reveal a major source of long-term wealth of the Haines family. Reuben Haines I speculated in real estate with considerable success during the second half of the eighteenth century. Besides valuable land holdings in Philadelphia, he purchased huge tracts in northern and central Pennsylvania which his descendants inherited and variously rented or sold for cash profits.
  The documents concerning the family's Philadelphia and Germantown properties are of interest for information on 18th and 19th century land divisions, notably on Second, Fourth, and Market Streets in Philadelphia, and on Germantown Avenue, Walnut Lane, Haines Street, and High Street in Germantown.
  Finally, this series as a whole furnishes examples of the style and format of legal materials over a period of 250 years.
  The material in this section is divided into two categories. The first category is organized by name followed by an alphabetical subject file.
  The second category regards real estate and is arranged according to location and date of document. Oversized material is listed following each category.
  - PART I
    - Dirk Jansen
      - Affidavit, 1737 (Box 225, Folder 1)
    - Reuben Haines I
      - Promissory notes, 1751-1778 (Box 225, Folder 2)
      - Bonds, 1752-1768 (Box 225, Folder 3)
      - Contract, 1753 (Box 225, Folder 4)
      - Contract with Samuel Wallis, 1767 (Box 225, Folder 5)
      - Bonds, 1769-1770 (Box 225, Folder 6)
      - Bonds, 1771-1772 (Box 225, Folder 7)
      - Bonds, 1773, 1774 (Box 225, Folder 8)
      - Mortgages, 1774, 1777 (Box 225, Folder 9)
      - Bonds, 1775 (Box 225, Folder 10)
      - Bonds, 1776, 1777 (Box 225, Folder 11)
      - Bonds, 1778-1783 (Box 225, Folder 12)
      - Promissory note, 1779-1793 (Box 225, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous legal papers re. court suit; Milnor and Haines vs. Mumford, 1738-1791 (Box 225, Folder 14)
      - Bonds, 1784, 1785 (Box 225, Folder 15)
      - Power of attorney Dennis Leary to Reuben Haines, 1786 (Box 225, Folder 15a)
      - Bonds, 1786, 1787 (Box 225, Folder 16)
      - Mortgage, 1787 (Box 225, Folder 17)
      - Bonds, 1788, 1789 (Box 225, Folder 18)
      - Bonds, 1790-1793 (Box 225, Folder 19)
      - Re. bonds, 1791 (Box 225, Folder 20)
      - Settlement of partnerships with Bartholomew Wistar and CWH I, 1792 (Box 225, Folder 21)
      - Lists of bonds, 1797 (Box 225, Folder 22)
      - Eviction notice, n.d. (Box 225, Folder 23)
    - Margaret Wistar Haines
      - Bond, 1785 (Box 225, Folder 24)
    - Richard Hartshorne
      - Bond, 1808 (Box 226, Folder 25)
      - Letter of attorney, 1836 (Box 226, Folder 26)
    - Catharine Haines Hartshorne
      - Bonds, 1795 (Box 226, Folder 27)
      - `Rules of Reference' re. bonds to CHH, 1795 (Box 226, Folder 28)
      - Marriage settlement, 1799 (Box 226, Folder 29)
    - Caspar Wistar Haines I
      - Promissory notes, 1785-1798 (Box 226, Folder 30)
      - Bonds, 1786-1801 (Box 226, Folder 31)
      - `Agreement' with CHH and Josiah Haines, 1794 (Box 226, Folder 32)
      - Lists of bonds, 1797-1805 (Box 226, Folder 33)
      - `Rules of Reference' re. bonds to CWH I, 1798 (Box 226, Folder 34)
      - Letter of attorney, 1799 (Box 226, Folder 35)
      - Deed in trust, 1799 (Box 226, Folder 36)
      - Promissory note, 1801 (Box 226, Folder 37)
      - Lists of partnerships in which CWH I was concerned, n.d. (Box 226, Folder 38)
    - Josiah Haines
      - Contract; brewery partnership agreement with G. Twells and C. Morris, 1794 (Box 226, Folder 39)
      - Bond, 1795 (Box 226, Folder 40)
    - Reuben Haines II
      - Letter of attorney, 1791 (Box 226, Folder 41)
    - Hannah Marshall Haines
      - Lists of properties belonging to HMH, 1803 (Box 226, Folder 42)
      - Bond, 1817 (Box 226, Folder 43)
    - Reuben Haines III
      - Contracts, 1808-1829 (Box 226, Folder 44)
      - Notice of bankruptcy, Richard Green to Reuben Haines., 1812 (Box 226, Folder 44a)
      - Bonds, 1813-1831 (Box 226, Folder 45)
      - Letter of attorney, promissory note, 1814 (Box 226, Folder 46)
      - re. law suit; Dickey vs. PH III, 1820 (Box 226, Folder 47)
      - Contracts re. Italian Village; agreement between Rafinesque and Spence, 1823, 1826 (Box 226, Folder 48)
      - Mortgage settlement, 1828 (Box 226, Folder 49)
      - List of properties, n.d. (Box 226, Folder 50)
    - Jane Bowne Haines I